Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Advertisements Collection, 1950-1991 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Advertisements collection 1950-1991 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office.
126 linear feet Extent: 6300 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The JWT Frankfurt (Germany) office opened in 1952 and served as the main JWT office in Germany, and directed many of JWT's pan-European advertising efforts. The Frankfurt Office Advertisements Collection spans the years 1950 through 1991 and includes newspaper and magazine print advertisements, tear sheets and proofs. Clients include BASF, Burger King, De Beers, Dunlop, Ford, Kraft, Lever Brothers, Pan Am, and Singer. Most advertisements are in German, although some are in English. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00691
Language: Material in English and German
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Advertisements Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 1994.
Collection Overview
The Frankfurt Office Advertisements Collection spans the years 1950 through 1991 and includes newspaper and magazine print advertisements, tear sheets and proofs. Clients include BASF, Burger King, De Beers, Dunlop, Ford, Kraft, Lever Brothers, Pan Am, and Singer. Most advertisements are in German, although some are in English.
Collection is arranged by format size and product name.
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office; Badische Anilin- & Soda-Fabrik; Burger King Corporation; De Beers Consolidated Mines; Dunlop Rubber Company; Ford Motor Company; Kraft Foods Company; Lever Brothers and Unilever, ltd; Pan American World Airways; Pan American Airways Corporation; Singer Sewing Machine Company; Advertising; Advertising -- Germany; Advertising -- Germany -- History -- 20th century; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Germany; Advertising agencies -- History -- 20th century; Advertising campaigns; Advertising campaigns -- Germany; Clippings; Proofs; Tear sheets; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Frankfurt Office Records
International Advertisements Collection
Newsletter Collection
Publications Collection
Contents of Collection
- Small Format Advertisements
  - Alpi (Box 1)
    - Consumer, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
    - Trade, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Collateral, 1966-1969 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - Alpi (continued) (Box 2)
    - Consumer, 1971-1982 (Box 2)
    - Trade, 1971-1973; 1976-1986 (Box 2)
    - Collateral, 1970-1981 (Box 2)
  - ACSA, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Adepe, 1966-1969 (Box 3)
  - Adams, undated (Box 3)
  - Air Zaire, undated (Box 3)
  - Aktion Freizeit, undated (Box 3)
  - Aktion Gemeinsinn, undated (Box 3)
  - Alcan, 1959-1966 (Box 3)
  - American Express, undated (Box 3)
  - Artes, undated (Box 3)
  - Australische Botschaft, undated (Box 3)
  - BASF, 1964-1966 (Box 4)
  - BASF (continued), 1967-1968; 1972 (Box 5)
  - BASF (continued), 1972; 1979 (Box 6)
  - Bissel, 1960-1966 (Box 7)
  - Birkel, 1966-1972 (Box 7)
  - Braun, 1971-1978 (Box 8)
  - Brinkman, 1960-1967; 1972-1974 (Box 9)
  - Bauparkasse, undated (Box 9)
  - Bristol-Meyers, 1960-1964 (Box 10)
  - Bacardi, 1970-1976 (Box 10)
  - Brown, Boverti, and Cie, 1968-1972 (Box 10)
  - British Petrol, 1954-1956 (Box 11)
  - W. Bauermann and Söhne (Boy Umbrellas), 1963-1971 (Box 12)
  - Bundesanleihen, 1966-1968 (Box 13)
  - Burger King, 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Burger King (continued), 1977-1982 (Box 14)
  - Baumgart Pelze, undated (Box 15)
  - BDS, undated (Box 15)
  - BDF (Beiersdorf AG), undated (Box 15)
  - Benetton, undated (Box 15)
  - Boeing, undated (Box 15)
  - Braemar, undated (Box 15)
  - Bremsley, undated (Box 15)
  - Buerlecithin, undated (Box 15)
  - Brass and Co., undated (Box 15)
  - BSA-Babybotte, undated (Box 15)
  - Burda, undated (Box 15)
  - Chevron/Celtey, 1963-1970 (Box 16)
  - Champion, 1960-1981 (Box 17)
  - Chevron, 1964-1978 (Box 18)
  - CMA, 1977-1979; 1982-1984 (Box 19)
  - Commodore, 1983-1986 (Box 19)
  - Computerland, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Coti, 1976-1978 (Box 19)
  - Countless Mara, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Cushman, 1968 (Box 19)
  - Copygraph, 1970 (Box 19)
  - Coca-Cola, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Chesebrough-Ponds, 1954-1968 (Box 20)
  - Champagne King, circa 1987 (Box 20)
  - California Raisin Board, 1960-1961; 1965; 1968 (Box 20)
  - Campari, 1980-1983; 1986 (Box 20)
  - Canada Mink Breeders, 1962-1964 (Box 20)
  - Deutsche Bank, undated (Box 21)
  - Deutsche Welle, 1971 (Box 22)
  - Dorian, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Deutsche Bundesbank, 1965-1968 (Box 22)
  - Dymo, 1969-1975 (Box 22)
  - Douglas, 1955-1968 (Box 22)
  - Deutsches Weinsiegel, undated (Box 22)
  - Dortmunder Ritterbrauerei, 1971-1974; 1978; undated (Box 22)
  - DeBeers, 1967-1974 (Box 23)
  - DeBeers (continued), 1975-1979 (Box 24)
  - DeBeers (continued), 1980-1994 (Box 25)
  - Deutsche Burroughs, undated (Box 26)
  - Douglas, undated (Box 26)
  - Deutscher Wein, 1969-1976 (Box 27)
  - Deutscher Wein (continued), 1977-1987 (Box 28)
  - Dunlop (Box 29)
    - General, 1958-1971 (Box 29)
    - Dunlopillo Mattress and Bedding, 1958-1971 (Box 29)
  - Dunlop (continued) (Box 30)
    - General, undated (Box 30)
    - Dunloplan Floor Covering, 1960-1971; undated (Box 30)
  - Dunlop (continued) (Box 31)
    - Sports Equipment and Clothes, 1967-1972 (Box 31)
  - Dunlop (continued) (Box 32)
    - Corporate, 1952-1957; 1967-1969; 1973; undated (Box 32)
    - Tires, 1954-1959 (Box 32)
  - Dunlop (continued) (Box 33)
    - Tires, 1960-1967 (Box 33)
  - Dunlop (continued) (Box 34)
    - Tires, 1968-1969 (Box 34)
  - Dunlop (continued) (Box 35)
    - Tires, 1970-1972 (Box 35)
  - Dunlop (continued) (Box 36)
    - Tires, 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Einbecker, 1971-1975 (Box 37)
  - Einbecker (continued), 1977-1980 (Box 38)
  - Eaton, undated (Box 38)
  - Eckes Wein, undated (Box 38)
  - Eckes Koch, undated (Box 38)
  - Eilerbracht, undated (Box 38)
  - Elbschloss, undated (Box 38)
  - Eurotax, undated (Box 38)
  - En Vogue, undated (Box 38)
  - Elida, 1953-1960 (Box 39)
  - Elida (continued), 1962-1984 (Box 40)
  - Ford, 1950-1956 (Box 41)
  - Ford (continued), 1956-1960 (Box 42)
  - Ford (continued), 1957-1958; 1960-1961 (Box 43)
  - Ford (continued), 1962-1963 (Box 44)
  - Ford (continued), 1964 (Box 45)
  - Ford (continued), 1965-Collateral material, 1965 (Box 46)
  - Ford (continued), 1965-1966-Consumer, trade, and collateral material (Box 47)
  - Ford (continued), 1966-collateral material (Box 48)
  - Ford (continued), 1966-1967-consumer and collateral material (Box 49)
  - Ford (continued), 1967-collateral material, (Box 1 of 2) (Box 50)
  - Ford (continued), 1967-collateral material, (Box 2 of 2) (Box 51)
  - Ford (continued), 1968 (Box 52)
  - Ford (continued), 1969-1970 (Box 53)
  - Ford (continued), 1970-collateral material 1971-consumer, trade, and collateral material (Box 54)
  - Ford (continued), 1972-1973 (Box 55)
  - Philco Ford, 1970-1972 (Box 55)
  - Ford (continued), 1974-1977 (Box 56)
  - Ford (continued), 1978-1979 (Box 57)
  - Ford (continued), 1979-1983 (Box 58)
  - Ford (continued), 1984-1985 (Box 59)
  - Folienfabrik Forschheim, undated (Box 60)
  - Frankfut International School, undated (Box 60)
  - Faberge, undated (Box 60)
  - Carl Freudenberg, undated (Box 60)
  - David Feldman, Ltd., undated (Box 60)
  - Blexalum Blinds, undated (Box 60)
  - Finanzbanken, undated (Box 60)
  - Frankfurter Hypothekenbank, undated (Box 60)
  - Fichtel and Sachs, undated (Box 60)
  - Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung (FAZ), undated (Box 60)
  - First National City Bank, undated (Box 60)
  - FIMA, undated (Box 61)
  - Famous Schools International, undated (Box 61)
  - Fachverband der Berliner Damensberkleidungsindustrie, undated (Box 61)
  - Gluckauf, undated (Box 62)
  - Gramco, undated (Box 62)
  - Garrett International, undated (Box 62)
  - Goldman Sachs, undated (Box 62)
  - Gummi Mayer, undated (Box 62)
  - Goldpragung, undated (Box 62)
  - GECA, undated (Box 62)
  - Gayal, undated (Box 62)
  - Geigy, undated (Box 62)
  - Gillette, undated (Box 62)
  - Glucksklee, 1968-1970 (Box 63)
  - Glucksklee (continued), 1970-1972 (Box 64)
  - Glucksklee (continued), 1972-1981 (Box 65)
  - Hoffman, undated (Box 66)
  - Heinzelmann, undated (Box 67)
  - Höchst, undated (Box 67)
  - Harley Davidson, undated (Box 67)
  - Hultsch, undated (Box 67)
  - Hallmark, undated (Box 67)
  - Holiday Inn, undated (Box 67)
  - Hercules, undated (Box 67)
  - IZE, undated (Box 68)
  - IHC/IHV (Hotel Organizations), undated (Box 68)
  - Irische Außenhandelstelle, undated (Box 68)
  - Irische Fremdenverkehrszentrale, undated (Box 68)
  - Irving Trust, undated (Box 68)
  - Isenburg Zentrum, undated (Box 68)
  - IMA, undated (Box 68)
  - IFA, undated (Box 68)
  - IGL, undated (Box 68)
  - JOPA, undated (Box 69)
  - Johnson, undated (Box 70)
  - Jacobs, undated (Box 71)
  - J. B. Williams, undated (Box 71)
  - JWT, undated (Box 72)
  - Kraft, 1957-1964 (Box 73)
  - Kraft (continued), 1965-1968 (Box 74)
  - Kraft (continued), 1969-1971 (Box 75)
  - Kraft (continued), 1972-1975 (Box 76)
  - Kraft (continued), 1976-1981 (Box 77)
  - Kraft (continued), 1980-1988 (Box 78)
  - Karakul Industry Advisory Board (Swakara Furs), undated (Box 78)
  - Kuratorium DL. Altershilfe, undated (Box 78)
  - Kalle Infotec, undated (Box 78)
  - Kodak, undated (Box 79)
  - Kaufhof, 1967-1972 (Box 79)
  - Kaufhof, 1973-1986; undated (Box 80)
  - Kellogg, undated (Box 81)
  - Listermint, undated (Box 82)
  - Löwen Brauerei (Schultheiss), undated (Box 82)
  - Lohse, undated (Box 82)
  - Lebensversicherung, undated (Box 82)
  - Lavex, undated (Box 82)
  - Luxaflex, undated (Box 82)
  - Lefévre Utile, undated (Box 82)
  - Lysoform, undated (Box 82)
  - Litton Industries, undated (Box 82)
  - Lever/Sunlicht, 1956-1959 (Box 83)
  - Lever/Sunlicht (continued), 1959-1962 (Box 84)
  - Lever/Sunlicht (continued), 1963-1965 (Box 85)
  - Lever/Sunlicht (continued), 1966-1968 (Box 86)
  - Lever/Sunlicht (continued), 1969-1980; undated (Box 87)
  - Maggi, 1958-1965 (Box 88)
  - Maggi (continued), 1966-1972 (Box 89)
  - Minnesota Mining, 1965-1967 (Box 90)
  - Malaysia, undated (Box 91)
  - Mead Papers, undated (Box 91)
  - Molto, undated (Box 91)
  - Mr. Kipling Cakes, undated (Box 91)
  - Merrill Lynch, undated (Box 91)
  - Minnesota Mining, 1960-1965 (Box 91)
  - Much, undated (Box 92)
  - [Mirof], undated (Box 92)
  - Miles, undated (Box 92)
  - Monroe, undated (Box 92)
  - Malaysia Bank, undated (Box 92)
  - Minimal, 1987-1990 (Box 93)
  - Minimal (continued), 1991 (Box 94)
  - Melka, undated (Box 94)
  - Möbel Franz, undated (Box 94)
  - Mapa, undated (Box 94)
  - Murine, undated (Box 94)
  - Messe-Interstoff, undated (Box 94)
  - Norda, 1972-1975 (Box 95)
  - Nittel, undated (Box 95)
  - Nicholas, undated (Box 95)
  - Norda, 1960-1969 (Box 96)
  - Nestle, undated (Box 97)
  - New Holland, undated (Box 97)
  - Nicolaus Packaging, undated (Box 97)
  - Nesquick, undated (Box 97)
  - National Airlines, undated (Box 97)
  - Okal, undated (Box 98)
  - Olivetti, 1967-1969 (Box 98)
  - Ouzo, undated (Box 98)
  - Outboard, undated (Box 98)
  - Olivetti, 1969-1974 (Box 99)
  - Pan Am, 1955-1965 (Box 100)
  - Pan Am (continued), 1966 (Box 101)
  - Pan Am (continued), 1967-1969 (Box 102)
  - Pan Am (continued), 1970-1978 (Box 103)
  - Papierfabrik Seltmans, undated (Box 103)
  - Philips, undated (Box 103)
  - Pino, undated (Box 103)
  - Pioneer, undated (Box 103)
  - Prue Acton, undated (Box 103)
  - Platin, undated (Box 104)
  - Pepsi, 1962-1969 (Box 105)
  - Pepsi (continued), 1970-1979 (Box 106)
  - Qualitätsschutzverband der Kürschner, undated (Box 107)
  - Pelikan, undated (Box 107)
  - Pfeilring, undated (Box 107)
  - Royal Canadian Mint, undated (Box 108)
  - Reese, undated (Box 108)
  - Rheinland Versicherung, undated (Box 108)
  - Readers Digest, undated (Box 108)
  - Rowntree, undated (Box 108)
  - Rosenthal, undated (Box 108)
  - RCA, undated (Box 108)
  - Ronnico, undated (Box 108)
  - R. J. Reynolds, undated (Box 108)
  - Ritter, undated (Box 109)
  - Rolex, undated (Box 110)
  - Shannon Airport, undated (Box 111)
  - Schwedische Elementhäuser, undated (Box 111)
  - Shell Chemical, undated (Box 111)
  - Ski Cigarettes, undated (Box 111)
  - Spanish Tourism Board, undated (Box 111)
  - Sperry Rand--Ford Instrument, undated (Box 111)
  - Stock, undated (Box 111)
  - Schloß Rheinberg Juwell, undated (Box 111)
  - Schaumann Animal Feed, undated (Box 111)
  - Singer, 1965-1968 (Box 112)
  - Singer (continued), 1968-1969 (Box 113)
  - Singer (continued), 1970-1972 (Box 114)
  - Singer (continued), 1973-1974; 1980 (Box 115)
  - Schwab Versand, undated (Box 115)
  - Schwarzkopf, undated (Box 115)
  - Suwa, undated (Box 115)
  - Seagram’s, undated (Box 116)
  - Sisley, undated (Box 116)
  - Sprengel, undated (Box 116)
  - Söhnlein, undated (Box 116)
  - SAGA and SWAPL/Scandinavian Fur Committee, undated (Box 117)
  - Swakara, undated (Box 118)
  - Schultheiss, undated (Box 119)
  - T2, undated (Box 120)
  - Tabasco, undated (Box 120)
  - Tate and Lyle, undated (Box 120)
  - Teledyne, undated (Box 120)
  - Thera Chemie, undated (Box 120)
  - Time-Life, undated (Box 120)
  - Tradica, undated (Box 120)
  - Trans World Investments, undated (Box 120)
  - Trim Jeans, undated (Box 120)
  - Triumph, undated (Box 120)
  - Tefal, undated (Box 120)
  - Varta, undated (Box 121)
  - Vereinigte Papierwerke, undated (Box 121)
  - Union Castle, undated (Box 122)
  - US Air, undated (Box 122)
  - US Top, undated (Box 122)
  - Vitapan, undated (Box 122)
  - Velter, undated (Box 122)
  - VAG, undated (Box 122)
  - Verein für Zahnhygiene, undated (Box 122)
  - Verband der Chemischen Industrie, undated (Box 122)
  - Warner, undated (Box 122)
  - Woelm, undated (Box 122)
  - Wick, 1972-1986 (Box 123)
  - WEGA, undated (Box 123)
  - Western Gear, undated (Box 123)
  - Westminister Bank, undated (Box 123)
  - Wrangler, undated (Box 123)
  - Wimpy, undated (Box 123)
  - Winston, undated (Box 123)
  - Wrigley’s, undated (Box 123)
  - Wolf, undated (Box 123)
  - Wick, 1960-1971 (Box 124)
- Large Format Advertisements
  - American Home, undated (Box 125)
  - Arbeitsgruppe Kommunikation, undated (Box 125)
  - Aktion Gemeinsam, undated (Box 125)
  - BAG, undated (Box 125)
  - Bayer, undated (Box 125)
  - BAT, undated (Box 125)
  - Batburg, undated (Box 125)
  - Berliner Chic, undated (Box 125)
  - Bundesministerium für Gesundheitswesen, undated (Box 125)
  - Burda, undated (Box 125)
  - BASF (including Spanish), 1966-1972 (Box 125A)
  - Champion spark plug, 1968-1976 (Box 125B)
  - Eastman Chemical, undated (Box 125B)
  - McDonnell Douglas, undated (Box 125B)
  - Murine, undated (Box 125B)
  - Wrangler jeans, 1971 (Box 125B)
  - Chevron, undated (Box 126)
  - CMA, undated (Box 126)
  - Copygraph, undated (Box 126)
  - Cushman, undated (Box 126)
  - Cheseborough-Pond’s, 1957-1963 (Box 126)
  - Dunlop (Box 127)
    - Dunlopillo, 1959-1970 (Box 127)
    - Dunloplan, 1955-1958, 1967-1968, undated (Box 127)
  - Dunlop (continued), 1962-1965 (Box 128)
  - Dunlop (continued), 1966 (Box 129)
  - Deutsche Burroughs, undated (Box 130)
  - Deutsche Bank, undated (Box 130)
  - Deutscher Wein, undated (Box 130)
  - Dunlop, 1968-1974; undated (Box 130)
  - De Beers, undated (Box 131)
  - Douglas, undated (Box 131)
  - Ducros, undated (Box 131)
  - Deutsche Bundesbank, undated (Box 131)
  - Drive, undated (Box 131)
  - Dortmunder Ritterbrauerei, undated (Box 131)
  - Deutscher Wein, undated (Box 131)
  - Dr. Kippe, undated (Box 131)
  - Dymo (Box 131)
  - Elbschloss, undated (Box 132)
  - Einbecker, undated (Box 132)
  - Eaton, undated (Box 132)
  - Eternit, undated (Box 132)
  - Eckes Wein, undated (Box 132)
  - Elida, 1960-1982 (Box 133)
  - Ford, 1957-1959 (Box 134)
  - Ford (continued), 1960-1966 (Box 135)
  - Ford (continued), 1966-1967 (Box 136)
  - Ford (continued), 1967-1970 (Box 137)
  - Ford (continued), 1971, (Box 1 of 2) (Box 138)
  - Ford (continued), 1971, (Box 2 of 2) (Box 139)
  - Ford (continued), 1972 (Box 140)
  - Ford (continued), 1971-1973 (Box 141)
  - Ford (continued), 1974 (Box 142)
  - Ford (continued), 1975-1976 (Box 143)
  - Ford (continued), 1976 (Box 144)
  - Ford (continued), 1977 (Box 145)
  - Ford (continued), 1978-1979 (Box 146)
  - Ford (continued), 1971-1981 (Box 147)
  - Ford (continued), 1980 (Box 148)
  - Ford (continued), 1981-1982 (Box 149)
  - Ford (continued), 1983-1985 (Box 150)
  - FAZ, undated (Box 151)
  - Fahlberg, undated (Box 151)
  - FFE, undated (Box 151)
  - Famous School International, undated (Box 151)
  - Fachverband der Berliner Dameoberbekleidungsindustrie, undated (Box 151)
  - FIMA (Fischwirtschaftliches Marketingsinstitut), undated (Box 151)
  - Glücksklee, 1967-1970 (Box 152)
  - Garrett, undated (Box 153)
  - Geigy, undated (Box 153)
  - Gillette, undated (Box 153)
  - Glücksklee, 1970-1980 (Box 153)
  - Glückauf, undated (Box 153)
  - Gramco, undated (Box 153)
  - Gummi Mayer, undated (Box 153)
  - Hoffmann, 1965-1977 (Box 154)
  - Heinzelmann, undated (Box 155)
  - Hercules, undated (Box 155)
  - Hultsch, undated (Box 155)
  - Hallmark, undated (Box 155)
  - Holiday Inn, undated (Box 155)
  - Hoffmann, 1962-1964 (Box 155)
  - IGL, undated (Box 156)
  - Interstoff-Messe, undated (Box 156)
  - IFA, undated (Box 156)
  - Irische Fremdenverkehrszentrale, undated (Box 156)
  - Irische Außenhandelstelle, undated (Box 156)
  - Isenberg Zentrum, undated (Box 156)
  - Irving Trust, undated (Box 156)
  - Intercontinental Hotels (IHC), undated (Box 156)
  - Internationale Hotelverbetungen, undated (Box 156)
  - Jopa, 1963-1966 (Box 157)
  - Jacobs, undated (Box 158)
  - Johnson, undated (Box 158)
  - Jopa, 1967-1968 (Box 158)
  - JWT, undated (Box 158)
  - Kraft, 1960-1983 (Box 159)
  - Kaufhof, undated (Box 160)
  - Kalle Infotec, undated (Box 161)
  - Karakul (Swakara Furs), undated (Box 161)
  - Kent, undated (Box 161)
  - Kodak, undated (Box 161)
  - Kellogg’s, undated (Box 161)
  - Kubel, undated (Box 161)
  - Kuratorium dL. Altershilfe, undated (Box 161)
  - Liggett and Myers, undated (Box 162)
  - Lefèvre Utile, undated (Box 162)
  - Lohse, undated (Box 162)
  - Lever/Sunlicht, 1959-1961 (Box 162)
  - Lever/Sunlicht (continued), 1963-1965 (Box 163)
  - Lever/Sunlicht (continued), 1966-1985; undated (Box 164)
  - Minnesota Mining, undated (Box 165)
  - Maggi, undated (Box 165)
  - Minimal, 1989 (Box 166)
  - Minimal (continued), 1987-1988 (Box 167)
  - Minimal (continued), 1990 (Box 168)
  - Minimal (continued), 1991 (Box 169)
  - Monroe, undated (Box 169)
  - Mr. Kipling Cakes, undated (Box 169)
  - Merrill Lynch, undated (Box 169)
  - Nordsee/Norda, 1960-1972 (Box 170)
  - Nicolaus Packaging, undated (Box 171)
  - New Holland, undated (Box 171)
  - National Airline, undated (Box 171)
  - Nicholas, undated (Box 171)
  - Nestle, undated (Box 171)
  - Nittel, undated (Box 171)
  - Outboard, undated (Box 171)
  - Olivetti, undated (Box 171)
  - Olivetti (continued), 1967-1974 (Box 172)
  - Omega, undated (Box 172)
  - Pan Am, 1955-1967 (Box 173)
  - Pan Am, 1968-1970 (Box 174)
  - Pan Am, 1971-1977 (Box 175)
  - Philip Morris, undated (Box 175)
  - Platin, undated (Box 175)
  - Pelikan, undated (Box 176)
  - Pfeilring, undated (Box 176)
  - Pepsi, undated (Box 176)
  - RJ Reynolds, undated (Box 177)
  - Ritter, undated (Box 177)
  - Reese, undated (Box 177)
  - Rolex, undated (Box 177)
  - RCA, undated (Box 177)
  - Singer, 1967-1971 (Box 178)
  - Singer (continued), 1972-1974 (Box 179)
  - Singer (continued), circa 1966 (Box 180)
  - Söhnlein, undated (Box 181)
  - SAGA/Scandinavian Fur Committee, undated (Box 181)
  - Seagram’s, undated (Box 181)
  - Sisley, undated (Box 181)
  - Sprengel, undated (Box 181)
  - Swakara, undated (Box 181)
  - Silvodor, undated (Box 182)
  - Scott Paper, undated (Box 182)
  - Schwab Versand, undated (Box 182)
  - Südmilch, undated (Box 183)
  - Schwarzkopf, undated (Box 183)
  - SUWA, undated (Box 183)
  - Schultheiss, undated (Box 184)
  - Schultheiss, undated (Box 185)
  - Tefal, undated (Box 185)
  - Triumph, undated (Box 186)
  - Time-Life, undated (Box 186)
  - Tate & Lyle, undated (Box 186)
  - VAG, undated (Box 186)
  - Varta, undated (Box 186)
  - Vetter, undated (Box 186)
  - Vereinigte Papierwerke, undated (Box 186)
  - Verband der Chem. Industrie, undated (Box 186)
  - Verein für Zahnhygiene, undated (Box 186)
  - Vitapan, undated (Box 186)
  - Volkswagen, undated (Box 186)
  - US Top, 1982 (Box 187)
  - Wick, 1959-1961 (Box 187)
  - Zewa, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 187)
  - Wick, 1966-1985 (Box 188)
  - Wick (continued), 1962-1964 (Box 189)
  - Warner, undated (Box 189)
  - Woelm Pharma, undated (Box 189)